Barskov Nikita

Data Engineer at Maxifier. Master Degree Student at Samara University.

9 Samara, Russia

J +7(927)657-16-10

github.com/nikitabarskov

in linkedin.com/in/nikitabarskov

⋪ t.me/nikitabarskov

Professional Summary

I am a data engineer, an enthusiast for developing intelligent and modern applications that improve the quality of using and presenting data. I've got 2 years experience with implementing ETL with frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos. I'm well known in Python data analysis libraries, mathematical packages, and visualization tools.

I'm a bachelor of applied mathematics and physics with close to excellent average score (4.75/5.0). All mathematical and software engineer exercises have done with excellent score. My academic mathematical background allows me to take advantages of statistic, calculus and algebra methods for transforming data as I need and extracting necessary information for my work and needs.

I'm a Master of Science at Samara University with an excellent (5.0/5.0 at the moment) average score. My Master's thesis theme is «Forecasting users interacting with advertising content on sites» relates to job specific at Maxifier.

Experience

Maxifier, Samara, Russia

Intern April 2017 – June 2017

Working on batch processing project in Maxifier as Intern.

Stack: Java, Guice, PostgreSQL, Spark, Hadoop, Aurora, Bazel, GitLab Cl.

Data Engineer June 2017 – Present

Developing the application for forecasting users interactions with advertising content and its evaluation. Stack: Python/Scala, Spark, Hadoop, Mesos, Docker, MySQL, Akka, Slick, SciPy, Maven, GitHub.

Education

Samara University, Samara Russia

Master Degree Student
Data Analysis and Quality Assurance, Average Point 5.0

Bachelor of Science

Applied Mathematics and Physics, Average Point 4.65

September 2017 – June 2019

Sep 2013 – June 2017

Skills

Personal: rational, responsible, sociable

Base Skills: advanced knowledge in mathematics and application of these methods to ETL

Natural Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

Programming Languages: Python 3 (intermediate knowledge for writing batch processing jobs and data

science), Scala, Java (regular knowledge for writing services and batch processing jobs)

Frameworks and libraries: Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos, Docker, Scipy(Pandas, Numpy,

Matplotlib), Scikit-learn, Akka, Slick

Build Tools and VCS: Maven, Bazel, Git, Gitlab CI, Github

Others: knowledge in process cycle of Software Application Development, methodologies, QA, Bussiness and System Analytics